Finding Aid for College of Literature, Science and the Arts (University of Michigan) records, 1846-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Associate Dean for Undergraduate Education 1954-2011
  - General Files 1992-2001
    - Topical 1992-2001
      - Internships
        - Political Internships (Box 467)
      - Interuniversity Consortium for Political Science and Social Research (ICPSR) (Box 467)
      - Kellogg (Box 468)
      - Key Administrators Group (Box 468)
      - Kyrgyzstan University President's Visit (Box 468)
      - Language Across the Curriculum (LAC)
        - Correspondence (Box 468)
        - Courses (Box 468)
        - Interested Faculty (Box 468)
        - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Proposal (Box 468)
      - Language Across the Curriculum (LAC) Committee (Box 468)
      - Leadership Initiatives (Box 468)
      - Lecturers (Box 468)
      - Library (Box 468)
      - Living-Learning Programs/Learning Communities (MLC), 2 folders
        - Graduate Student Proposal (Box 468)
        - Living-Learning Program Task Force Final Report August 1996 (Box 468)
        - Working Groups: Recruitment (Box 468)
      - Lund Delegation Visit (Box 468)
      - Managers Meeting (Box 468)
      - Massachusetts Law School (Box 468)
      - May Seminars (Box 468)
      - McPhearson, Michael (Box 468)
      - Meet Togethers (Joint Offerings) (Box 468)
      - Mellon, Andrew W. Foundation (Box 468)
      - Mentoring Junior Faculty (Box 468)
      - Mentorship Program (Box 468)
      - Michigan Arts Initiative (Box 468)
      - Michigan Community College Association (Box 468)
      - Michigan Hispanic Education Award (Box 468)
      - Michigan Humanities Award (Box 468)
      - Michigan Science Scholars (Box 468)
      - Migrant Worker Program: English as a Second Language (ESL)-Latino Studies (Box 468)
      - Minority Equity, Office of (OME)
        - Proposal submitted by the Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program (UROP) (Box 468)
        - Select Student Services Program Grant (Box 468)
      - Minority Retention (Box 469)
        - Minority Retention Programs External Review (Box 469)
      - Miscellaneous Meetings (Box 469)
      - M-Pathways (Box 469)
      - M-Ties (Box 469)
      - National Learning Communities Project (Box 469)
      - National Medal of Science (Box 469)
      - National Science Foundation (NSF): Computer and Information Science, and Engineering (CISE) Educational Infrastructure Program (Box 469)
      - Neuman, Shirley, 4 folders (Box 469)
      - Neuroscience Laboratory Building Executive Committee (Box 469)
      - Organizational Studies, 2 folders (Box 469)
      - Outreach (Box 469)
      - Outside Programs (Box 469)
      - Overseas Internship Awards (Box 469)
      - Parents' Weekend (Box 469)
      - Pew Scholars Program (Box 469)
      - Pilot Grant (Box 469)
      - Political Science, Department of: Strategic Plan (Box 469)
      - Pre-Health (Box 469)
      - Pre-Med Advising (Box 469)
      - President's Office: Lee Bollinger (Box 469)
      - Program Enhancement Initiative (Box 469)
      - Project Flame (Box 469)
      - Project Kaleidoscope (Box 469)
      - Provost Office Initiative: Dining Discussion Pilot Program (Box 469)
      - Provost's May Retreat (Box 469)
      - Public Health, School of (Box 469)
      - Quantitative Reasoning Task Force Report February 1993 (Box 469)
      - Race or Ethnicity/University Course 299 Board Review Committee (Box 469)
      - Rackham (Box 470)
      - Reaccreditation (Box 470)
      - Reading/Learning Skills Center (Box 470)
      - Recognition Award for the Integration of Research and Education (RAIRE)
        - Advisory Committee (Box 470)
      - Recruitment, 2 folders (Box 470)
      - Recruitment Director Search (Box 474)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2030 ]
      - Reibstein, David (Box 474)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2028 ]
      - Research Based Learning (Box 470)
      - Research on Learning and Teaching, Center for (CRLT)
        - Faculty Development Fund Award (Box 470)
        - Whitaker Grant (Box 470)
      - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) Committee, 2 folders (Box 470)
      - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) Course Credit Task Force (Box 470)
      - Residential College (RC)/LSA Liaison Committee, 2 folders (Box 470)
      - Resolution Officers (Box 470)
      - Retroactive Credit (Box 470)
      - Sale of Class Notes and Student Papers (Box 470)
      - Saturday Seminars (Box 470)
      - Saudi Visit (Box 470)
      - Scholarship Program (Box 470)
      - Science Education (Box 470)
      - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA) (Box 470)
      - Sexual Assault Prevention and Awareness Center (SAPAC) (Box 470)
      - Social Research, Institute for (ISR) (Box 470)
      - Social Work (Box 470)
      - Society and Medicine, Program in (Box 470)
      - Staff Fellowship Program (Box 470)
      - Steneck, Margaret L. (Box 474)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2025 ]
      - Student Government (Box 471)
      - Student Information: Graduate/Undergraduate (Box 471)
      - Students with Disabilities, Office of (Box 471)
      - Summer Institutes (Box 471)
      - Summer Programs
        - History Department Pilot Program (Box 471)
      - Tasmania, University of Exchange (Box 471)
      - Teach for America (Box 471)
      - Teaching with Technology: Mini-Grants (Box 471)
      - Teachers as Scholars (TAS)
        - Proposals in Social Science (Box 471)
      - Telluride (Box 471)
      - Tenure Analysis Study (Box 471)
      - Theme Semesters (Box 471)
      - Transfer Credit (Box 471)
      - Travel and Hosting Policies (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Admissions Advisory Committee (UAAC), 5 folders (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Clubs (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Education Committees, 2 folders (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Education Initiatives (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Research Requirement (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Staff Meetings (Box 471)
      - Undergraduate Student Services Group (Box 471)
      - University Course Division (Box 471)
      - University of Michigan Television (Box 471)
      - Vice Provost for the Arts: Paul Boylan (Box 471)
      - Visiting Committee (Box 471)
      - Waterman Award (Box 472)
      - Weinberg, Martha (Box 474)
      - Weisner Symposium (Box 472)
      - Welcome to Michigan (Box 472)
      - Writing Review (Box 472)
  - Martin, Michael 1989-1994
    - Alliance for Minority Participation, 2 folders (Box 472)
    - Comprehensive Undergraduate Education in Science, Math, and English (Box 472)
    - Counseling, 2 folders (Box 472)
    - Detroit Extension (Box 472)
    - Engineering College, 2 folders (Box 472)
    - First Year Outcomes, Task Force on (Box 472)
    - First Year Experience (FYE)
      - Assessment Instruction (Box 472)
      - Background File, 2 folders (Box 472)
      - Freshman Seminar/Learning Community (Box 472)
      - Mentorship Project, Outreach, Community Service, Interest Groups (Box 472)
    - First Year Seminars (Box 472)
    - Global College (Box 472)
    - Goals (Box 472)
    - Grants-Applied for (Box 472)
    - Information Technology Division (ITD) (Box 472)
    - Institute for Central American Development Studies (ICADS) (Box 473)
    - Interdisciplinary Teaching and Research (Box 473)
    - Language Instruction (Box 473)
    - Language Instruction Task Force, 3 folders (Box 473)
    - LSA/Engineering Math Committee (Box 473)
    - LSA Summary (Box 473)
    - Long-Range Planning and Analysis (Box 473)
    - Math Proposal to the National Science Foundation (NSF) (Box 473)
    - Neuroscience, Center of (Box 473)
    - Physics Proposal to the Department of Education (DOE) (Box 473)
    - Physics Proposal to the National Science Foundation (NSF) (Box 473)
    - Pre-Health Profession Advising (Box 473)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Funds Fellowship (Box 473)
    - Science Education
      - Proposals and Initiatives (Box 473)
      - Seminars (Box 473)
    - Science Learning Center (SLC), 2 folders (Box 473)
  - Joint Faculty-Student Policy Committee (JFSPC) 1977-2000
    - Agendas and Minutes/ Emerging Issues, 1995-96 (Box 515)
    - Articles (Box 515)
    - Report: Building Undergraduate Academic Communities and Delivering Student Support Services, 1994-95 (Box 515)
    - Academic Judiciary Committee
      - Academic Integrity, Codes and Standards of (other institutions) 1990-1994 (Box 515)
      - Academic Judiciary Structure and Process, Broader Concerns of Academic Integrity circa 1970-2000 (Box 515)
      - Changes to Faculty Code Language 1997 (Box 515)
    - Academic Judiciary Committee
      - Faculty Comments 1993-1994 (Box 515)
      - Handouts and Reports 1994-1995 (Box 515)
      - Information on Academic Judiciary 1977-1997 (Box 516)
      - Legal Suggestions, Concerns, Notes 1994 (Box 516)
      - Letter to LSA Faculty and Students re: Academic Integrity & Mission Statement 1995 (Box 516)
      - Review of the LS&A Academic Judiciary: Request for Comments 1994 (Box 516)
      - Review of the LS&A Academic Judiciary 1994 (Box 516)
      - Student Grievance Procedure / College Referee 1975-1994 (Box 516)
    - Alcohol Issues
      - Alcohol and Drug Taskforce 1991-1994 (Box 516)
      - Alcohol Policy and Other Drugs 1991-1997 (Box 516)
      - Center for Great Lakes and Aquatic Sciences: Laurentian 1994 (Box 516)
    - Grading
      - Drop/Add: Academic Affairs 1995-1996 (Box 516)
      - Drop/Add: Articles 1995 (Box 516)
      - Drop/Add: Minutes and Policy Documentation 1995 (Box 516)
      - Drop/Add: Policies (Other Schools and Peer Universities) 1995-1996 (Box 516)
      - Drop/Add: Proposals 1995-1996 (Box 516)
      - Drop/Add: W Policies 1995-1996 (Box 516)
      - Drop/Add and Pass/Fail Statistics 2000 (Box 516)
      - Pass/Fail: 1975-1976 (Box 516)
      - Pass/Fail: 1994-1995 (Box 516)
      - Pass/Fail: 1984-1995 (Box 516)
      - Pass/Fail: 1995-2000 (Box 516)
      - Pass/Fail: Articles and research 1970-1996 (Box 516)
      - Pass/Fail: Graphs and Charts 1994 (Box 516)
    - Honors Program
      - Committee Members and Thank You Letters (Box 516)
      - UM Honors and Similar Programs at Other Colleges 1996-1997 (Box 516)
    - Language Requirements
      - Articles 1995-1996 (Box 516)
      - Background and Rationale 1951-1995 (Box 516)
      - Correspondence 1996 (Box 516)
      - Courses 1991-1996 (Box 516)
      - Enrollment Statistics 1993-1996 (Box 516)
      - Focus Group Meetings 1996 (Box 516)
      - Instructor Designed Questionnaire (IDQ) 1995 (Box 516)
      - Language Requirements 1988-1997 (Box 516)
      - Minutes 1996 (Box 516)
      - Placement into Courses 1996 (Box 516)
      - Preliminary Drafts 1996 (Box 516)
      - Proficiency 1985-1986 (Box 516)
      - Report: Second Language Instruction in the College of LSA 1996 (Box 516)
      - Student Government Survey and Ratings 1996 (Box 516)
      - Teaching Evaluations 1995 (Box 516)
      - Thank You Letters (Report) 1997 (Box 516)
      - UM & Peer University Policies 1991-1997 (Box 516)
    - Rush
      - Chapter Contact and Correspondence 1998 (Box 516)
      - Committee Input and Feedback 1997-1998 (Box 516)
      - Correspondence: Faculty and Advisor 1997-1998 (Box 516)
      - Correspondence: Greek Advisor 1998 (Box 516)
      - Correspondence: National 1998, 2 folders (Box 516)
      - Deferred Schools List and Interview Information 1998 (Box 516)
      - Financial Information 1997 (Box 517)
      - History of BGA, Latino/a and APA Chapters 1997 (Box 517)
      - Meeting Minutes 1998 (Box 517)
      - Report on Fall Term Fraternity/ Sorority Rush and Pledging 1998 (Box 517)
      - Research: Alcohol Abuse 1993-1998 (Box 517)
      - Research: Greek/ Sexual Assault 1994-1998 (Box 517)
      - Research: Rush/ Greek System 1995-1998 (Box 517)
      - Review of Fall Term Rush 1998 (Box 517)
      - Rush Schedules and Brochures 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - UM Articles and Editorials 1998 (Box 517)
    - Student Clubs
      - Articles 1998 (Box 517)
      - Contacts 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Correspondence 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Departmental Academic Clubs 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Funding 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Informational Materials 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Michigan Leadership Awards 1998 (Box 517)
      - Minutes 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Report: Developing and Strengthening Departmental Undergraduate Student Clubs 1998 (Box 517)
      - Student Government and Departmental Clubs 1997-1998 (Box 517)
  - General Files 1993-2011
    - Centers/ Departments/ Programs
      - Michigan Community Scholars Program-LUCY 2001-2003 (Box 517)
    - Topical
      - Departmental Award for Contributions to the Undergraduate Initiative 1996 (Box 517)
      - Faculty Code 2001 (Box 517)
      - First-Year Seminar Program
        - Report 1997 (Box 517)
        - LS&A First Year Seminars Program Review Final Report (Box 517)
      - Foreign-Language Review Committee
        - Report 2002-2003 (Box 517)
        - Background Materials 1993-1996 (Box 517)
      - Grade Inflation
        - Peer Institutions 1999 (Box 517)
        - Report: Grade Inflation and Grade-Point-Average Inflation in American Higher Education and in LS&A 1995 (Box 517)
        - Statistics 2000 (Box 517)
        - Research 1999-2000 (Box 517)
      - Graduate Student Instructor: Profile of GSI Usage and Training LS&A 1998-1999 (Box 517)
      - Language Resource Center
        - General 1994-1996 (Box 517)
        - Advisory Board 1994-1995 (Box 517)
      - Lloyd Hall Scholars Program 1996-1997 (Box 517)
      - Mason-Angell Hall arson 1997-1998 (Box 517)
      - Mathematics 1995-1999 (Box 517)
      - Promotion Recommendations-Issues 1997 (Box 517)
      - Reserve Officers Training Corps
        - Report: LS&A Degree Credit for ROTC Courses 1999 (Box 517)
        - Academic Credit: Background Materials 1999 (Box 517)
        - LSA ROTC Committee 1999 (Box 517)
      - Student Government Report (LSA) (Box 518)
        - 1998-1999 (Box 518)
        - 1999-2000 (Box 518)
        - 2000-2001 (Box 518)
        - 2001-2002 (Box 518)
        - 2002-2003 (Box 518)
        - Fall 2010 (Box 518)
        - Winter 2011 (Box 518)
      - Writing Review 1995, 2 folders
        - Writing Review for Pilot Project 1995 (Box 518)
- LS&A Development
  - Development Fund Scrapbook (Box 515)
    - 1977-1986, 3 folders (Box 515)
    - 1987-1991, 2 folders (Box 515)
    - 1991-1996, 2 folders (Box 515)
- Archived College of LS&A Website
  The College of LS&A Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the College of Literature, Science, and the Arts. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the College. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002 and 2003 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website capture May 15, 2002, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
    (Original URL http://www.lsa.umich.edu)
  - Website capture June 23, 2003, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Archived College of Literature, Science, and the Arts home page 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the College of Literature, Science, and the Arts 2010-[ongoing]